GERMÁN OVALLE SILVA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- govalle3@outlook.com
- +57 (316)-538-6121
- linkedin.com/in/german-andres-ovalle-silva

I am a responsible, organized, creative mechatronic engineer with ease of teamwork, troubleshooting. I have 5 years of knowledge in Java, Databases, Cloud Computing, SQL, UML and SCRUM abilities.

I enjoy web programming and I have been interested in AI software development. I'm currently updating and expanding my knowledge in this digital age.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Java developer.

Globant.

Medellín - Antioquia

Jan, 2022 - Current

PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPER -

Consultant client: Customer project within the price to automate the authentication and authorization process through authorization based on permissions with different identity providers (Idp) according to the one used by the client to provide him with a list of web applications for each company (client) that can be monitored and can add users with permissions to access these web applications. Project from scratch using VDI, java 17 zulu, Azure devops, spring web, spring reactive. Postgresql

Responsabilities: responsible for the fulfillment of user stories within each sprint of the entire backend team.





Development of a full stack SCRUM project in java 17 with spring and ports and adapters architecture, postgre sql as database engine, for the nodejs frontend and angular framework.

- GLOBANT CLIENT Internal project for delivery work items to the globers (employees), backend and DB team leader for a full stack project developed in java 11, microservices architecture application hosted in an aws cluster developed in spring boot 2.6.7, spring data jpa, aurora postgresql, mapstruct, lombok, junit suite, sonar, aws s3, github enterprise, git, scrum methodologies.
- OPENBANK- Fintech industry Bank client with microservices
 architecture, Java 11, Java 17,
 Spring framework, Aws services
 (SQS, event Bridge, collection Flow),
 PostgreSQL, unit testing and
 integration testing, continuous
 integration with bamboo.
- OPENBANK CORE Core Bank client - migration from legacy apps to java 11, AWS services, DynamoDB, Oracle DB, unit testing and integration testing, continuous integration with jenkins and sonar. Creation of new functionalities based on microservices architecture,

GERMÁN OVALLE SILVA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

applying SOLID principles. Creation of business logic and crud endpoints.

Responsabilities: Management of invoices, execute business logic and save it in databases per microservice, AWS data lake process calculations and executes payments into the core banking to process the transaction.

Develop capacity of professionals who can run Banking Software integration and customization projects.

Move clients from captive technology (JBasic) to open platforms (java) with plenty of available workforce.

Software developer architect Ceiba Software House SAS. Medellín - Antioquia Mar, 2020 - Jan. 2022

- SURA Inssurance CO Development project with ports And Adapters architecture in Java, Scala, PlaySlick with MySql, implementing unit tests and integration with PlayTest, Expose and consume endpoints.
- SURA CORE Development project in Guidewire (gosu language) and Oracle at core, managing the contact address book, configuration of message queues in RabbitMQ using AMQP model configuring attributes of headers, bindings and routing keys, creating producer and consumer for insert or modify contacts from the address book.

Parking system client - with Ports and Adapters Architecture, using Java 8, Gradle, Spring Boot framework for the backend, Spring Data JPA to persist the data in MySql database, and consumption of REST services from an Angular 6. Responsible for developing the business logic implementing TDD, using Lambas, Streams, Optionals, OOP and Functional Programming, following quality standards and clean code. Creation of unit tests to the domain with test data builder and AAA pattern.

Controller integration tests using MockMVC and H2 in-memory database. Load testing with Jmeter. Continuous Integration with Jenkins and SonarQube for static code analysis.

 Technologies used: Java 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Gradle, Spring Data JPA, Spring Security, MySql, JUnit4, Mockito, MockMVC, H2, Github, Jenkins, SonarQube, SCRUM and Jira.

Freelancer

Freelance, Fiverr (Working Apps). Jan, 2019 - Mar, 2020

Working as freelance developer

 Develop projects for website design , landing pages, configuring full design of web page for e-commerce with shopify running adds.

GERMÁN OVALLE SILVA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Development of a full stack project for sales management in a local store using PostgreSQL as a local database engine, Java 1.8, spring boot, using rest web services for communication between the frontend and the backend via http. Angular framework, js.

Full Stack Developer
National Army of Colombia.
Engineering Battalion No.5 Dr.
Francisco Jose Caldas.
Bucaramanga, Colombia
Mar, 2018 - Jan, 2019

 Develop project for using Spring, Java, SQL Server, UI design with HTML, CSS, Angular, JS, Ports And Adapters architecture. Project for attendance record of the employees and visitors to the military unit of intelligence agency.

Using biometric sensors and search of criminal records using API's from headquarters.

Responsabilities: support on new backend functionalities, development of business logic.

 (Security College US) as internal auditor in information security.

TECH KNOWLEDGE

- JAVA SE POO
- SOLID principles applied.
- Spring Framework
- Spring mvc Security.
- Spring Boot
- Spring JPA- Hibernate
- Spring Cloud
- Java Stream API.
- Java Functional Programming.
- Liquid Base, Flyway
- · Scala & Play.
- PostgreSQL, Oracle DB
- SQLite y MySQL.
- MongoDB
- Amazon Web Services EC2, Sandbox evironment, Remote debug.
- Git & GitHub Professional.
- Deployment,
- DOCKER Containers

EDUCATION

Universidad Autónoma de Bucaramanga Mechatronics Engineer Jan, 2013 - Jan, 2018 Bucaramanga, Colombia

Honors

- Patent "Rehabilitation machine for lower limb with 3 degrees of freedom". NUM NC2018/0007555.
- Biennial researcher and project development